Aaron Burmeister

207-992-6009 | <u>aaronburmeister91@gmail.com</u> <u>Github | LinkedIn | Blog | aaronburmeister.tech</u>

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in genetics. Strong academic background in sciences, including a Master's in Bioinformatics. Familiar with production environments from donuts and coffee to DNA genotyping. Determined hard worker, always willing to learn new things and collaborate on cross-functional teams. Avid gamer, including video games and tabletop games, especially D&D.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Ember, Photoshop, Windows, Linux, Git, Cypress, SQL, PostgreSQL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Collaboration Station (Alpha) - Github | Demo

A Rails/Ember.js app designed to be a central hub for D&D players and artists to connect and commission work.

- Learned a new framework, Ember.js, in 4 days
- Developed a Rails API backend using PostgreSQL with endpoints for users, images, and requests
- Provided images with an overlay function to view as an overlay on the screen

Flatiron Finder - Github | Demo | Deployed

A Rails/Vanilla JavaScript designed to facilitate social connections between Flatiron School students

- A single-page app using Vanilla JavaScript and devised profile-picture creator through the Cloudinary API
- Utilizes JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Developed a Rails API backend using PostgreSQL with endpoints for users and technologies
- Enables users to search for other users via several different filters: name, campus, cohort, language, and framework

Brew n' Review - Github | Demo

A Rails/Vanilla Javascript app designed as a journal for beer enthusiasts to search for beers by name or brewery

- Developed a Rails API backend using SQLite3 with endpoints for beers, styles, users, styles, and reviews
- Created a user interface using vanilla JavaScript, allowing the user to write, edit, and delete their reviews

WORK EXPERIENCE

The Jackson Laboratory

Improvement Specialist

Bar Harbor, ME

04/2019 - 10/2019

- Contributed to the Object Relational Mapping of a Flask API with almost no prior Python experience
- Tested and developed the automation of Melt Curve Analysis on the Intelliqube
- Optimized the use of a costly enzyme (Tag Polymerase) through test-driven methods

Genotyping Technician

07/2014 - 04/2019

- Provided customers with a quick turnaround time on request and reprioritized work to meet customer deadlines
- Ensured maintenance of machines, organization of workspace, and upkeep of supplies to prevent slowdowns

Dunkin Donuts

Ellsworth, ME

Crew Member

07/2009 – 10/2014

- Provided accurate, quality service at drive-through, averaging 2-3 minutes per order, exceeding corporate standards
- Managed cashier operations, up to several thousand dollars per shift, and calculated transactions with low error rate
- Maintained supplies and serviced machines to ensure smooth store operations
- Fostered a jovial work environment through strong personal connections with coworkers

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Denver, CO

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

01/2020 - 04/2020

University of Maine at Orono

Professional Science Masters (PSM) in Bioinformatics

Orono, ME 05/ 2020

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute

Troy, NY

Bachelor of Science (BS) in Biochemistry & Biophysics

05/2014